We want first person, singularis, present, to stay here and now.
I teach so too many different groups.
At one point I had under and nurses in the group.
The nurses were recent graduates and had their education in the body.
They had a hard time writing "I".
It became "man", and hovered away in abstractions.
The nurses had no problems with it.
However, they spelled as rakes, but it was easy to do something about it.
It is interesting to see what our education does to us,
And what perspectives we get worse at.
But that does not mean that it is uneducable.
Instead, we have something we do not yet know.
It becomes clear when writing a research application.
Then you have to talk about everything you know, and extensive what we do not know.
And then I'll talk about exactly how to find out.
I have acquaintances who got the noble because they did not talk about
Exactly in which magazines to publish what they do not yet know.
I have to know a lot for not knowing exactly that.
Few researchers feel comfortable with it, because this is not possible.
It would not be research if it went so.
Here Cusanus becomes extremely liberating to think with.
It is from this perspective that non-knowing becomes relevant.
In modernity, we do not perceive horizons of non-science, but see it as a wall.
Christianity is not without the advancement here.
On the other side of the wall we have a god and a heavenly.
A lot of things we can't know anything about.
On this page we have the world, which we can create knowledge about.
The modern man says: “Why should I relate to what we can't know?
I stand with my back against the horizons and look at knowledge production.
In this world - nature, what can be measured.
Weber says that modernity is the time where we do not care about non-scientific.
The relationship between the wall and a horizon can be considered for a long time.
When we focus on ratio, intellectus does not disappear.
This is faith, here is knowing.
Culture is society's foremost practice to think about what is important.
Today when we are in a collective crisis to the environmental issue, the art is there and pondering.
What is it to be human?
It is there and examines at once.
The culture becomes incomprehensible.
After we arrange the world, it is nice with flute games.
Or it becomes culture for health.
There is always a risk that culture will be an instrument for something else.
We do not understand the Intellectus activities.
It is the same with the relationship between science and the humanities.
The last powerpoint said: "Whatever you do, care for your quality registers."
And that was exactly what happened.
The quality registers are there for the care of the elderly to be better.
But we have seen that the purpose of the purpose carries more with it.
It has become more important to care for the quality registers than the elderly.
We care for the elderly to enter the right figures in the documentation monster.
It is a clear displacement that is harmful.
At the Health Care Association, they say that those who think the papers are important are those who can remain.
Those who focus on healthcare are moving from there.
It is a dangerous system.
Teachers and nurses are the shortcomings, and that is not because we educate too few.
That's because they don't want to stay.
What they trained for is not there.
The job has been to feed the paper monster.
It is a concrete experience for many.
In this situation, something is haunting.
What is the reason when it is a ratio without intellectus?
That's exactly the reason the computer has.
Partly it is one and zeros - things either are or are not.
A computer is either or in the basic structure.
It fits well into manual thinking.
While a human being can think analogously in sliding scales.
With a sensitivity to another side of the language.
Imagine the poetic, which tries to be close to the concrete.
Computer logic has become an ideal.
People also have a ratio, because we have made the computers.
Where we have feelings and values, we try to get rid of it.
This allows the computer to come close but it remains a hearing.
Therefore, the rationality of the computer is never fully enough.
Human language is hearing, but the intellectus's competence is to be in contact with the round.
I think it is clear why the concrete is important.
When we enter the concepts, it is easy to become pure fool production.
This school's key words - the student at the center, respect, learning.
We throw out clichés, and so it will be no more.
Teachers talk about respect, but not about who should have respect for what.
It just becomes a word you hit each other in their heads.
Floskel production becomes our way when we do not understand the intellectus business.
In the skeptical thought apparatus, one should lift yourself from the contemporary ration that exists.
If we know all the time, we can't see anything else.
We will show that much of what is being done is not about increasing the quality of the floor.
It's about showing off.
It's something else.
Words like "ensure" I think we should dismay.
It's almost always a lie.
At Södertörn, they said they would ensure that no abuse happens again.
How should you do then?
Lock everyone in each room?
Many things cannot be ensured, and then it becomes spasmodic.
We will work qualitatively with such issues.
It will be like a safety hub.
The measurement becomes a cutting -edge.
We can measure, and we will measure, but in a wise way.
- It made me think a lot about the steering document concept.